Register of the Sergei N. Klaminskii holograph: Al'bom pamiati doblesti, slavy i chesti rossiiskoi imperatorskoi armii i flota s IX-go po XX vek n.d.
Hoover Institution Archives
Sergei N. Klaminskii holograph: Al'bom pamiati doblesti, slavy i chesti rossiiskoi imperatorskoi armii i flota s IX-go po XX vek
n.d.
2000C13
Klaminskii, Sergei Nikolaevich
18 microfilm reels. (2.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Relates to Russian military history, especially during the period of World War I and the Russian Revolution and Civil War. Microfilm.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Location of Originals
Original in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Access Points
Russia--History, Military.; World War, 1914-1918--Russia.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Campaigns.; World War, 1914-1918.; Russia.; Soviet Union.
Biography
Russian Imperial army officer
Scope and Content
This collection consists of a twenty-one-volume handwritten and illustrated history of the Russian army, 862-1922. Of particular interest are the volumes covering the late Imperial years and Civil War, in which the author, himself a military officer, was able to comment on historical events as a participant. Volumes 10, 19 and 20 are devoted exclusively to uniforms, military schools and institutes, and histories of the various regiments.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials and copyright to them (with some exceptions) are the property of the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Container List
- "Al'bom pamiati doblesti, slavy i chesti Rossiiskoi Imperatorskoi armii i flota c IX-go po XX vek" Bound manuscript history of the Russian army, 862-1922. The twenty-one volumes are arranged chronologically by title, except for the final three thematic volumes, Boxes 1-20
  - "S IX po XVII vek" (Box 1., Volume 1)
  - "S 1613 po 1725: Pervye Romanovy do Petra I vkl." (Box 2., Volume 2)
  - "Epokha Imp. Imp. Ekateriny I, Petra II, Elizavety, Petra III, Ekateriny II i Pavla I" (Box 3., Volume 3)
  - "Imp. Aleksandr I, 1801-1812 g.g." (Box 4., Volume 4)
  - "Imp. Aleksandr I, 1812-1825 g.g." (Box 5., Volume 5)
  - "1825-1855 g." (Box 6., Volume 6)
  - "1855-1881" (Box 7., Volume 7)
  - "S 1881 po 1894" (Box 8., Volume 8)
  - "1894-1905" (Box 9., Volume 9)
  - "Formy." Includes information on military organization and uniforms, detailed descriptions and illustrations of uniforms, badges, insignia and medals, covering the first two decades of the XXth century (Box 10., Volume 10)
  - "1905-1914" (Box 11., Volume 11)
  - "1914" (Box 12., Volume 12)
  - "1915" (Box 13., Volume 13)
  - "1916" (Box 14., Volume 14)
  - "1917" (Box 15., Volume 15)
  - "1918." This and the following volumes dealing with the Russian Civil War cover exclusively the military operations of the White Armies (Box 16., Volume 16)
  - "1919" (Box 17., Volume 17)
  - "1920 i dalee" (Box 18., Volume 18)
  - "Istoriia polkov." Chronological fact sheets on Guards, infantry, cavalry, artillery units and Cossack hosts (Box 19., Volume 19)
  - "Voenno-uchebnye zavedeniia." Brief histories of military schools, institutes and academies (Box 20., Volume 20)
  - Untitled. Consists of brief biographies of famous Russian military commanders, with a list of all field marshals, and histories of Russian medals. Includes Dvukhsotletie intendantstva, 1700-1900, St. Petersburg, 1900 (Volume 21)